Guide to the Anita Burdman Feferman Papers SC1206
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Anita Burdman Feferman papers
1932-2001, bulk 1993-1996
bulk
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Feferman, Solomon.
Feferman, Anita Burdman.
SC1206
6.5 Linear Feet (6 cassette boxes, one half-manuscript box, 1 carton, 1 media box)
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
Audio interviews conducted for Feferman's book, Alfred Tarski: Life and Logic, which she co-authored with her husband Solomon Feferman.
Biographical/Historical note
Anita Burdman Feferman and her husband Solomon Feferman are the co-authors of a biography of the logician Alfred Tarski. Solomon Feferman is Professor of Mathematics and Philosophy, Emeritus and Patrick Suppes Professor of Humanities and Sciences, Emeritus at Stanford University. Alfred Tarski was Solomon Feferman's doctoral adviser at UC Berkeley.
Logicians -- United States -- Biography.; Logic, Symbolic and Mathematical.; Tarski, Alfred; Feferman, Solomon.; Feferman, Anita Burdman.
- Interviews
  - Herschs of Zurich, 1.1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Ginette Henkin, 1.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Gaifman, 1.3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Gaifman, 1995 Sep 28; 1.4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - FENSTAD, 1994 Jun 29; 1.5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Dyson Verena, 1995 Jan 9; 1.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Verena Dyson, 1995 Jan 20; 1.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Persi Diaconis & Part 2 of Kelley, 1995 Aug 21; 1.8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Davidson, 1994; 1.9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Constance on Julia & Tarski, 1995 Oct; 1.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - C. C. Chang, 1995 Feb 19; 1.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - C. C. Chang, 1995 Feb 19; 1.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - David Blackwell, 1.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Kathleen Chuaqui, 1996 Jan 30; 1.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Addison & Craig, 1994 Mar 4; 1.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Witeska (Sister in law), 1995 Feb 10; 2.1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Verena, 2.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Vaughts, 1994 Mar 4; 2.3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Sluga, Hans, 1995 Apr 14; 2.4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Szczerba, 1993 Sep 5; 2.5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Michael Rabin, 1994-04-06; 2.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Dale Ogar, 1995 Sep 14; 2.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Mycielski, 1994 Sep 11; 2.8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Mostowska, 1993 Sep; 2.9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Madeline Moore, 1994-1996; 2.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Milosa, 1994 Oct 21; 2.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Ralph McKenzie, 1995 Dec 11; 2.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Henkin, 1993 Dec 1; 2.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Kelley, 1995 Aug 16; 2.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - David Kaplan, 1995 Feb 17; 2.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Don Kalish, 1995 Feb 17; 2.16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Jan Takski & Urzula, 1984 Dec; 2.17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Zawdorosky, 1996 Sep 8; 3.1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Vaught, 3.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Magidor & Wolenski, 1996 Aug; 3.3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Jan Tarski & Sarah Hallam, 1994 Jan; 3.4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Life in Poland, 1994 Jan 10; 3.5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - War in Poland, 1994 Jan 1; 3.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Ina Tarski, 1993 Oct 12; 3.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Ina Tarski, 1993 Oct 12; 3.8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - 8 Minutes of Notes, 1995 Apr 12; 3.9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Suppes, 1995 Apr 12; 3.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Dana Scott, 1994 May 12; 3.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Warsaw, 1993; 3.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Louise Rothstein, 3.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Hilary Putnam Lecture, 1994 Apr 25; 3.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Pacholski, 1994 Jul; 3.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Lee Hause, 1995 Sep; 3.16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Halmos, 1996 Nov 5; 3.17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Mrs. Borsuk, 1996 Sep 7; 3.18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Sarah Hallow & Celina Whitfield, 4.1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Celina Whitefield, 4.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Blog Seminar on Tarski, Oct 6; 4.3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Pete Wells, 1995 Mar 10; 4.4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Wells, 1995 Mar 10; 4.5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Feferman on Tarski, 4.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Zalewski: Lodz Jews, 5.1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Emelia W. S. Letters, 5.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Helson, 5.3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Mycielski, 1997 May; 5.4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Siekierski, 5.5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - A. Szmielew, Warsaw, 1997 Jun 30; 5.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Tadeusz Translations (Letters), 5.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Nycielski Bancroft Letter, May 23; 5.8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Marin Smith Tarski, 1997 Mar 12; 5.9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Kotarbiuski Translation, 5.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Corcoran, 1997 May 8; 5.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Guine on Tarski, 1997 Mar 21; 5.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Weibe & Corcoran, 1997 May; 5.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Ina Tarski, 1997 Apr; 5.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - June Lewin, 6.1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Pawlak, 6.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Pawlak II, 6.3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Julia Robinson, 6.4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Fred Thompson, 6.5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Fred Thompson, 6.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Ken Arrow, 6.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Eilenberg, 6.8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Benson Mates, 1991 Jan 10; 6.9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Benson Mates, 6.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Grigorch, 6.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Odd bits From January, 6.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Polish man, 6.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Butler, 6.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Hempl, 6.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - D. Morel, 6.16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Peter Hoffman, 6.17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Trevor McMinn, 6.18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Tadeus translations, 6.19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Dorothy Wolfe, 6.20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Tarski, Alfred, 1978 Mar 25; 6.21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Symposium, 1965 Apr; 6.22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Tarski "Memory Session", 2001 May 28; 6.23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Preller, 1997 August; 6.24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Oswaldo Chateaworiand (Boston), 1998 August; 6.25; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Wilfred Hodges, 6.26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Mostowski interviews, 6.27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Kotarbinska, 6.28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Os. Acad. Syrup: Kreisel & Following Discussion, 6.30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Cohen Follies, including Tarski episode, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 7)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2015-063
  - Tarski family tree (Box 1)
- Additional Material: Computer Disks, Accession ARCH-2016-082
  - Floppy Disks, 1993-1997; 16 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2018-050
  - WEDBERG + Papers - Jan Berg Good Info on Maria T. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Borsuk (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter for Borsluke to Tarski about Wanda's Death in response to T.S Letters (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter to Bochemski + Remisicences + Tarski Letter to Bochensk (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Jean (Regina) Butler Phd, 1948-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - C. C. Chang (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Corcoran (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chuagui, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Craig William (Bull) Information about Tarski Room (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Eilenberg (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter From Erdos (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Enderton + Tarski Tape Stories of Events for 1939 / The story of hearing hollow w/Balw (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ershov Affair (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Wisnovsky Sci Amen. Story, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Fevrier (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fevrier photos + text (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Gillman (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Givant on Kola Ashei o Beugelumi (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Givant + Verena - for the interviews, etc. Seventies / Givant + Portrait (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Grelling, von Kempski, Scholy, Lukasiewicz (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Borsuk, Grzegorczyk (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Sarah Helleon (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Helmer (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hersch interview 0 in Zurieh (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Notes - Hodges Himmon (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Wilfrid Hodes (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Peter Hoffman (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Vetena Huber-Dyson - RR.1 - Pander Island B.C. Canada (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Veena Letter to + fro Tarski / Huber Dyson (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Tarski at I.A.S Institute For Adu. Stu, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Ishiguro (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Tarski's Name + Brother's Fate / Rrynicki: Michal / Alexander - Jedrezjzcak (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Kokoszynska Letters (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Important Letters: Danas Letter of 1955, Steves letter of 1973, Zuine's Letter 1981, Eilenbergs Letter 5/1981, 1955, 1973, 1981 Jan, 1981 June (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Letters From Fishev / Gwpta - Inndia Trip / Ishigruo - Sherman Lecture Part / David Miller + Popper + Tarski (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Magidor, Meanadiw, 1996 Aug (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Mawia - in Berkeley Like a Housekeeper (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Benson Mates, 1994 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Ralpha Mckenzie - Interview 1966-, 1995 Dec 11 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - JCC McKinsey + Kaleski "Chen" (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Ame Doeris Morel- Delos Morel (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - David Miller ie Shearman Talk (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Milosz, Czeslaw (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Szymborska, Wislawa (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - RE Help for Maria Marcinmo's Interview w. Mme Kotarbuska translated by Hanna Walenoku, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Jan Mycialsla, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - NG, Judith (KC) letters from Ron Graham, 1962-1983 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Oppenheim, Feliy, Hemped, Diane (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - OBITS re Tarski. Poppers and Others, Struik, Dirk (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Pigozzi, Donald (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Preller, Anne Letter from Tarski, 1971 Oct 27 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Preller Anne + Fraisse (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Preller + Geilach Story (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Zuine (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Scott-Scihrier, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Szmielew, Alexander / Szielew, Wanda (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Sluga Good on Foegie Group, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Marianne Smith (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Ina Tarski + A. Ehren Foucht / Jan Tarski Notes (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Time Line - Some dates for Jan Tarski when Tarski went to Poland (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Thompson F.B (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Adam Ulam Coming to US, 1939 Sep (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Wells Metatongue (meta language to make meta love), 1962-1982 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Well's last emails on theses and Witkacy's Annotations (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Dorothy Walfe, Ina Scotts, … Richard Weibes Address / Golden Tears In the late 1950s (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Whitfield (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - 92 St "Y" MHA (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Witkacy (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Durer - Gerould - re: Witkacy (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Zawadowski (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Addison, John (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Addison's Stuff on Citatw (Box 1, Folder 72)